# **Luong Ngo**

Date of Birth: 25th April 1989

Address: 26<sup>th</sup> Diep Minh Chau, Tan Son Nhi, Tan Phu, HCM

Mobile: 0995455802

E-mail: ngocongluong@gmail.com

**Profile:** 

I'm Technical Architect and full-stack developer, hands-on developer over 5 year's experience working on a variety of projects from conception to release. I have a passion for develop new products, feel happy when my products is useful and used by many users. My approach is create a product that will be used by over 1.000.000 concurrent users and to be a good manager. I am a confident communicator and am comfortable working either independently or as part of a team with highly responsibility.

In 10-2015, I was lead team Windeliv win 2<sup>nd</sup> place over 450 contestants team at "Hackathon – Job search innovation" held by VietnamWork with product named CBOX. CBOX is an AI - a career assistant, using machine learning and natural language processing to ask and get information of users through chat and create CV for them.

## **Skills Summary:**

- Javascript, HTML5, CSS, ReactJS, Angularjs, Nodejs (Express, Loopback, SailsJS, ...), ...
- JAVA EE (Maven, JSF, JSP, ...)
- Goovy on Grail
- PHP Phalcon, Codeinigter, ...
- eJabber XMPP Server (Messaging server for realtime chat like Whatsapp, zalo, v.v...)
- Android (Android Studio, Graddle, GCM, Google Maps, Facebook SDK, XMPP aSMACK...)
- iOS (XCode, Cocoa pods, core data, AFNetworking, APNS, WebSocket, XMPPframework, v.v..)
- Ubuntu 14.04 server installed LAMP (apache, mysgl, php, ...), installed NGINX, security, ...
- MySql, Oracle database server, Postgresql, MongoDB, Redshift, ...
- Source code management (Git, SVN, v.v...)
- Countinous Integration (Jenkins, Bitbucket Pipeline), Docker, Vagrant.
- Web Services (Restful, Soap, Graphql)
- OpenAM SSO.
- Microservices architecture.

# **Education:**

 2007 – 2013 Ho Chi Minh University of Science Degree: Network Management.

#### **Employment History:**

# QueenB JSC

Java Developer, Team Leader

April 2012 - April 2014

Took an active role in the full development life-cycle.

- Worked closely with the customer to get information, business analysis, built products and fixed bugs.
- Successfully built and maintained a variety of customer-facing applications.(Dong Quang's Employee Management ,C2 Saigon Travel Tour Management KAPI, Tri Duc Pharmacy invoice, customer, employee management bSell, v.v...).
- From August 2013 working as Team Lead (4 members) and Project Manager.(2 Projects: Saigon Travel Tour Management KAPI and Tri Duc Pharmacy invoice, customer, employee management bSell).
- Maintained SQL databases and servers. (MySQL & Oracle)

## M SERVICE JSC

Developer

April 2014 – March 2015

- Worked in MIS team. Took role as core member in full development life-cycle.
- Fixed bug and maintained products.
- Maintained SQL databases and servers. (Oracle)

## ANDROBEAR CO.,LTD

Technical Lead, Team Leader

March 2015 - March 2016

- Played a crucial role in project planning by providing time estimates for completion of work.
- Researched and suggested conformed technology to build products.
- Undertook the responsibility of training junior developers, which involved compiling a suite of training materials.
- Researched and suggested conformed technology to build products.
- Lead team has 5 members include 2 web (PHP, Nodejs), 2 Mobile (1 Android, 1 iOS) and 1 designer. Also develop products as a developer.
- Successful in built and release 2 products on Apple Store and Google Store: Cancer (social network for Cancer Zodiac with over 1000 users), EasyJob (Social network for instant jobs with over 15000 users).

#### **SUTRIX SOLUTION**

Technical Architect

April 2016 - Present

- Support Project Manager on technical solutions for PHP, nodejs, infrastructure.
- Design system architecture for software (PHP, nodejs, infrastructure).
- Analyse system architecture of enterprise software.
- Setup continuous integration (Jenkins, Bitbucket Pipeline) & coding standards scanner (Sonar Qube) for projects.
- Manage Team Member and Team Leader on development for project quality.
- Training Team on NodeJS to help team improve their skill to work with high level technical client.
- Support Team on Code Review for guaranty code quality.
- Involve to projects as a senior developer to help team delivery ontime in some high workload projects.

- Communicate with high level technical client and help team to understand the technical specs.
- Giving technical solutions for some critical problems.
- Create Technical Specs Documents.

# **Additional Info:**

Preferred Work Location: Ho Chi Minh City Win 2<sup>nd</sup> Place at Hackathon 2015 held by Vietnamworks